RASHEEDAT AJIBORISHA

· +353 899758892 · rasheedatajiborisha@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An experienced Digital payments expert currently studying an Advanced Diploma in Full stack Software development with a demonstrated history in the POS and over 7 years' experience in Customer Service. An analytical problem solver with a track record of working under pressure, handling multiple tasks and prioritizing to meet deadlines. A proficient user of the Microsoft Office suite – Word, Outlook, PowerPoint & Excel with strong communication, strong collaboration, leadership and decision-making skills is looking for a place in the Customer and Technical Support Role with the HSE.

EDUCATION

MAY 2021 – Present **Diploma, Full stack Software development**

Code Institute, Dublin Ireland

SEPT 2006 – Aug 2009 **BSc Banking & Finance (2.1)**

Crescent University, Ogun Nigeria

WORK EXPERIENCE

JUN 2017 – March 2021 Acceptance Business Support Team Leader

Sterling Bank, Lagos Nigeria

- Managed the support team of 4 people in responding to merchants' queries/complaints through phone calls and emails regarding hardware or software issues with the POS and mobile acceptance products by guiding the merchants through steps to identify, access, resolve the issue and escalate when appropriate.
- Participated in pre-implementation efforts to identify any difficulties in the planned merchant POS and Mobile acceptance products' configuration as early as feasible to improve the customer go-live experience.
- Collaborated with the team to guarantee appropriate POS terminal registration and configuration by interacting with the processors and application developers.
- Ensured that all terminals and mobile acceptance products were subjected to a quality control test before being deployed to merchant locations.
- Checked and updated all the clients details i.e., name address and requests for the POS terminals and QR decals to enable appropriate settlements of transactions.
- Dealt with POS and mobile acceptance products requests from companies and individuals, carried out financial checks and onsite visits to assess if the business is a viable or profitable option to deploy payment acceptance products.
- Created an innovative technique to minimize service turn-around time while dealing with pos requests and treating support tickets on pos support portal.
- Assisted with the drafting and implementation of service level agreements between the bank and POS vendors/service providers.
- Ensured that all contractual obligations deriving from the POS business were met on time to prevent the bank suffering a loss due to default.
- Responsible for generating weekly/monthly statistics reports & creating presentations on the merchants' performance and activities.
- Generated a Quarterly Mastercard report on all transactions processed through the Bank's payments acceptance products which was required to identify transaction volumes, values, and specific locations.
- I coordinated with appropriate telecom firms and service providers to ensure that the POS businesses received the necessary services.

JUL 2014 - MAY 2017 Product Officer For E-Touchpoints Heritage Bank, Lagos Nigeria

- Carried out an evaluation of the merchants and their business location before deploying various electronic touchpoints i.e. POS terminals, ATMs and mobile payment kiosks
- Visited the merchants with the account officers to see if deploying of devices to this business will be profitable for the bank

- Provided first level support to POS merchants, answering customers queries regarding machine errors
- Troubleshot issues and talked merchants through the steps to fix the machines, became familiar with all the error codes in order to provide merchants with a timely and efficient solution
- Worked with the e-banking operations team to support POS merchants deal with any customer complaints around payments
- Conducted POS support trainings for different Bank branches.

Dec 2013 – June 2014 Client Relationship Officer

Unified Payments, Lagos Nigeria

- Worked with 3 banks to deal with merchant requests for POS terminals.
- Sourcing potential clients, meeting with the managers and providing presentations on the payment services the banks could provide.
- Linked the merchants with the relevant banking staff to programme and issue the POS terminals to their site.
- Created sales strategies to reach and exceed the quarterly POS terminal sales targets of 1500 units.
- Awarded a monthly bonus for regularly exceeding monthly sales targets.
- Managed the relationships with the client to provide point of sales and website payment solutions.

July 2012 – Nov 2013

Administrative Officer

Solution Enterprises Ogun Nigeria

- Carried out all administrative tasks for wholesalers of construction materials.
- Introduced digital payments, to move to a more efficient payment system and migrate from cash payments.
- Ensured that due diligence was carried out before goods were dispersed to companies, to ensure that the payment was received and verified.
- Carried out credit checks on customers and ensured that agreement forms were filled out when goods were to be bought on credit.
- Used the company portal to issue staff payments and entitlements i.e., Christmas bonuses or leave entitlements.

May 2011 - June 2012

Customer Care Officer (KYC)

Stanbic-IBTC Lagos Nigeria

- Confirmed that customers had completed all the requirements were before we could open their account.
- Input all the data into the bank portal in order to open their accounts i.e., customer name, address and place of work.
- Liaised with various departments to resolve customer issues regarding cards, transactions or payments.
- Talked the customer through their bank statements when there were transactions or payments that they did not recognize.
- Dealt with customer requests regarding opening accounts, payment of bills or fees and loans.

Nov 2009 - Oct. 2010

Yoruba Tutor (National Youth Service Scheme)

Elebele School, Bayelsa | Nigeria |

WORKSHOPS / TRAININGS

Feb 2019 – Mar 2019	Digital Payments: Keys to Deepen Financial Inclusion NIBSS Lagos Nigeria
Nov 2018 – Dec 2018	Payment Masterclass Interswitch Lagos Nigeria
Aug 2015- Sept 2015	Customer service Poise Finishing School Lagos Nigeria
Feb 2011 – Feb 2012	Total Personality Development Poise Graduate Finishing School Lagos Nigeria
Nov 2009 – Oct 2010	Campaigner Training Millenium Development Goal Awareness Bayelsa Nigeria

SKILLS

Microsoft Office – Word, PowerPoint, Excel and Outlook Computer Programming Languages - HTML, CSS, Python